Jesse Cambon

SUMMARY

Machine learning practitioner with broad experience delivering analytics products, developing software, and providing technical leadership. Creator of the R package tidygeocoder.

- Skills: Machine Learning Data Science NLP Statistics Software Development Data Visualization
- Tools: Python R SQL Git Linux AWS Azure

EXPERIENCE

Senior Data Scientist • Lighthouse

Mar 2022 - Present

• Trained deep learning NLP models for text classification on Azure with pytorch and deepspeed.

Senior Data Scientist • Embedded Healthcare

Mar 2021 - Feb 2022

- Embedded Healthcare was acquired by Clarify Health Solutions in 2022.
- Led analytics efforts to measure the impact of a key company intervention on healthcare utilization.
- Built data pipelines, data infrastructure, and quality assurance algorithms for critical project performance analysis.

Lead Data Scientist • Booz Allen Hamilton

Dec 2017 - Mar 2021

- Served as a technical lead and interim project lead. Managed 1-3 members of a data science team.
- Led the design and implementation of an NLP algorithm that used word embeddings to match employees to internal job opportunities. The algorithm was deployed as a web application for use by all employees and hiring managers.
- Overhauled and redesigned a python AWS Lambda application for enterprise-wide time charge accounting to provide efficient testing with AWS SAM, improved error handling, comprehensive data tracking, and smaller dependencies.
- Constructed regression models with Census microdata to analyze characteristics of metropolitan areas that attract immigrants. Presented at the 2018 Joint Statistical Meetings conference in Vancouver on behalf of DHS.

Analytics Consultant • Humana

Aug 2014 – Nov 2017

- Built a predictive model to identify social isolation in a population of 3 million Medicare members.
- Performed observational and randomized studies such as measuring the effects of vaccinations and blood sugar test compliance on medical costs.
- Published research in the American Health & Drug Benefits Journal on the impact of outreaches on out-of-network and emergency room utilization.
- Key analytic contributor to the survey design and analysis for a core company initiative featured in a Harvard School of Public Health case study.

PROJECTS

- Created the R package tidygeocoder which provides a uniform interface for using a variety of geocoding services. Tidygeocoder has over 100,000 downloads and was published in the Journal of Open Source Software (2021).
- Published blog posts on using R for data science that appear on R-Bloggers.com and RWeekly.org.
- Developed an image segmentation algorithm with Keras to identify cell nuclei for the 2018 Data Science Bowl.

EDUCATION

- University of Louisville M.Eng. & B.S, Mechanical Engineering, highest honors (2008 2013)
- University of Illinois / Coursera Accelerated Computer Science Fundamentals Specialization (3 courses on algorithms, data structures, and C++)
- DeepLearning.Al / Coursera 2 courses: Neural Networks and Deep Learning Improving Neural Networks